Guide to the American Federation of Teachers, Yakima Local 1485 Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
American Federation of Teachers, Yakima Local 1485 records
1969-1997
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
4145
American Federation of Teachers.$bLocal 1485 (Yakima Valley College)
12 cubic feet
Records of the local group affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers
Organized into 2 accessions.
Accession No. 4145-001, American Federation of Teachers, Yakima Local 1485 records, circa 1973-1984
Accession No. 4145-002, American Federation of Teachers, Yakima Local 1485 records, 1969-1997
Consult the scope and content information for each of the accessions listed below.
Consult the access restrictions information for each of the accessions listed below.
Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); American Federation of Teachers. Local 1485 (Yakima Valley College)$vArchives
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Labor History; Elementary and Secondary Education; Civic Activism; Washington (State)
- American Federation of Teachers, Yakima Local 1485 records, circa 1973-1984; 4145-001; 10 cubic feet
  Correspondence, minutes, newsletters, court files, grievances, arbitrations.
  Open to all users, but access to portions of the papers restricted. Contact repository for details.
  Donated by Ross Rieder Sept 17 and Dec. 1991.
  - PUBLICATIONS, 1968-1987; SERIES I
    - The Reformer, et al., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 4/26)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1969-1970 (Box-folder 4/25)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1969-1971 (Box-folder 4/23)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1972-1973 (Box-folder 4/28)
    - The Reformer, et al., Spring 1973 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1973-1974 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1974-1975 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1976-1977 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1977-1978 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1978-1979 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1979-1980 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1980-1981 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1981-1982 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1982-1983 (Box-folder ½)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1984-1985 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1985-1986 (Box-folder 4/29)
    - The Reformer, et al., 1986-1987 (Box-folder 4/24)
    - Local Publications, 1971 (Box-folder 4/22)
  - LEGAL CASES, GRIEVANCES, AND ARBITRATIONS, 1969-1988; SERIES II
    - Reduction in Force, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Horizontal Movement-Grievance, 1976 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Council for Postsecondary Education-Hearing, 1982 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Governor's Fact Finding Committee-Testimony, 1979 (Box-folder 1/40)
    - Notice of Assignment Form-Dispute, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 1/41)
    - Organization and Governance-Dispute, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 1/42)
    - Virginia Mack, 1976 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Phillips, Bonnie et al., 1978 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Phillips, et al. v. John Redmond, 1978 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Reduction in Force, 1981 (Box-folder 3/23)
    - Reduction in Force, 1981 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - Reduction in Force, 1981 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Nonrenewal (Pinkham, Mack, Jordan), 1975 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Information from District 16, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Reduction in Force, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - MacDonald, Hoague and Bayless (Harold Green), 1971 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Jerry Gaddy, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Printer-Collater Issue-Grievance, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Tayer, Delma, 1979 (Box-folder 4/31)
    - Redmond, John, 1978 (Box-folder 4/32)
    - Erb, Diana and Deborah Runge Unit Determination, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 4/33)
    - Erb, Diana and Deborah Runge Unit Determination, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 4/34)
    - Kerns, Joan, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 4/35)
    - Kerns, Joan-Grievance Bargaining Unit Status, 1979 (Box-folder 4/36)
    - Public Employment Relations Commission, 1977 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Public Employment Relations Commission-Unfair Labor Practices, 1977 (Box-folder 4/38)
    - Public Employment Relations Commission Hearing-Brief Regarding Challenges, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Public Employment Relations Commission Hearing-Brief Regarding Challenges, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Public Employment Relations Commission-Hearing Transcript, 1978 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Public Employment Relations Commission-Hearing Transcript, 1978 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Public Employment Relations Commission-Hearing Transcript, 1977 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Public Employment Relations Commission-Hearing Transcript, 1977 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Public Employment Relations Commission-Hearing Materials, December 15, 1977 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Ellis, Edward G., 1977 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Wells, Everett J., 1977 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Subpoenas, 1977 (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Dalton, Linda, 1977 (Box-folder 5/14)
    - Russell, William B., 1977 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Lyon, John D., 1977 (Box-folder 5/16)
    - Merriam, Shirley, 1977 (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Strain, Phyllis, 1977 (Box-folder 5/18)
    - Rickman, Paul, 1977 (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Vierra, Lester T., 1977 (Box-folder 5/20)
    - Talbot, Mary Lou, 1977 (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Ries, Margaret, 1977 (Box-folder 5/22)
    - Matheson, Merrie Jane, 1977 (Box-folder 5/23)
    - Mr. Carlstrom, 1977 (Box-folder 5/24)
    - Ackerman, Werner (Bill), 1977 (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Armstrong, Josephine, 1977 (Box-folder 5/26)
    - Barthell, Anna, 1977 (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Cowen, Don, 1977 (Box-folder 5/28)
    - Erland, Lowell, 1977 (Box-folder 5/29)
    - Falk, Cheryl, 1977 (Box-folder 5/30)
    - Foster, Sharon, 1977 (Box-folder 5/31)
    - Griffin, Richard, 1977 (Box-folder 5/32)
    - Hinman, Helen, 1977 (Box-folder 5/33)
    - Salary Suit-Final Papers, 1982 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Salary Suit-Final Papers, 1982 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Salary Suit-Final Papers, 1982 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Salary Suit-Final Papers, 1982 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Salary Suit-Privileged Documents, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Salary Suit-Privileged Documents, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Fisher, Robert, and Peterson Arbitration, 1984 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Fisher, Robert, and Peterson Arbitration, 1984 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Fisher, Robert, and Peterson Arbitration, 1984 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Fisher, Robert, and Peterson Arbitration-Exhibits, 1984 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Fisher, Robert, and Peterson Arbitration-Exhibits, 1984 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Analysis and Award, Carton J. Snow, Arbitrator, 1983 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Roddy and Ray Arbitration-Script of Testimony for Ray, Roddy, and Hanna, 1982 (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Roddy and Ray Arbitration-Opening Statement, 1982 (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Roddy and Ray Arbitration-Post Hearing Brief, 1982 (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Roddy and Ray Arbitration-Roy G. Roddy and Robert C. Ray, 1982 (Box-folder 6/20)
    - Roddy and Ray Arbitration-Roy G. Roddy and Robert C. Ray, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Roddy and Ray Arbitration-Roy G. Roddy and Robert C. Ray, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Briefs and Decisions, 103 Washington 2nd 391, 1985 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Salary Figures, 1986 (Box-folder 5/37)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Salary Figures, 1986 (Box-folder 5/38)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Salary Information, 1985 (Box-folder 5/35)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Legislative Aftermath, 1986 (Box-folder 5/36)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Correspondence with MacDonald, Hoague and Bayless, Attorneys at Law, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Depositions, 1983 (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Exhibits, 1983 (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Plaintiffs' First Interrogatories, 1983 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Plaintiffs' First Interrogatories and Requests, 1983 (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Plaintiffs' Exhibits in Support of Motion for Summary Judgment, 1983 (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Plaintiffs' Exhibits in Support of Motion for Summary Judgment, 1983 (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Summons and Petition and Complaint, 1982 (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Loose Papers, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Loose Papers, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Loose Papers, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Loose Papers and Newspapers, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5/39)
    - Carlstrom v. State-Loose Papers and Newspapers, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 5/40)
    - President's Advisory Council (II), 1982 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - President's Advisory Council (II), 1982 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - President's Advisory Council (I), 1982 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - President's Advisory Council (I), 1982 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - President's Advisory Council (I), 1982 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Toney, Carol, 1986 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Toney, Carol, 1986 (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Toney, Carol, 1986 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - McKenna, Barbara and Catherine Fousha, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 7/12)
    - McKenna, Barbara and Catherine Fousha, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 7/13)
    - McKenna, Barbara and Catherine Fousha, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 7/14)
    - McKenna, Barbara and Catherine Fousha, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 7/15)
    - McKenna/Fousha Arbitration-Exhibits, 1985 (Box-folder 7/19)
    - Workload and Compensation Grievance, 1985 (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Workload and Compensation Grievance, 1985 (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Workload and Compensation Grievance, 1985 (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Tenure Review Committee Recommendation for Non-Award of Tenure, 1981 (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Reduction in Force-Post Dismissal, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Reduction in Force-American Federation of Teachers Grant, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Reduction in Force, 1976 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Tenure Publications, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Carlstrom-Committee Hearing Letters, 1976 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Employment Issues, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Tenure Review Materials, 1976 (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Tenure Documents-Copies, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Tenure, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Phillips et al.-Tenure Review, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Scott, et al.-Arbitration transcript, 1978 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Scott, et al. v. Board of Trustees, 1978 (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Scott, et al. v. Board of Trustees, 1978 (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Black, David and Inga Wiehl Grievance, 1981 (Box-folder 8/14)
    - Black, David and Inga Wiehl Grievance, 1981 (Box-folder 8/15)
    - Black, David and Inga Wiehl Grievance, 1981 (Box-folder 8/16)
    - Workload Grievance, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8/17)
    - Workload Grievance, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8/18)
    - Wells v. President and Board of Trustees of Yakima Valley College, 1976 (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Wells Case-Loose Papers, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8/19)
    - Wells Case-Loose Papers, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8/20)
    - Wells Case-Loose Papers, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8/21)
    - Wells Case-Loose Papers, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8/22)
    - Wells Case-Loose Papers, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 8/23)
    - Wells Case-Appellants' Memorandum of Points and Authorities, 1977 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Draft of Response to Tenure Review Committee Recommendation, 1981 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Tenure Evaluation, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Baca and Phillips-Loose Papers, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Hicks, Arthur L.-Bargaining Unit Status, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Mr. Faller's Copy-Grievance, 1978 (Box-folder 9/16)
    - Crosier et al. v. Yakima Valley Community College District 16, 1978 (Box-folder 9/17)
    - Crosier et al. v. Yakima Valley Community College District 16, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 9/18)
    - Crosier, Ellwood-Faculty Assignment, 1982 (Box-folder 9/19)
    - Lord, Richard, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 9/20)
    - Tenure, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 9/23)
    - Court Case, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 10/22)
    - Court Case, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 10/23)
    - Court Case, 1966 (Box-folder 10/26)
    - Court Case, Yakima, 1966 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - EXECUTIVE BOARD MEETINGS, 1964-1988; SERIES III
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1964 (Box-folder 4/21)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 1/28)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1974 (Box-folder 10/18)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 10/17)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1976 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1981 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1982 (Box-folder 1/39)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1983 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 1/36)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Executive Board Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 3/20)
  - UNION BUSINESS, 1965-1983; SERIES IV
    - Survey, Full Time, 1981 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Survey, Full Time, 1979 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Survey, Full Time, Fall 1972 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Full Time Day Faculty, 1971 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Part Time, 1987 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - New Members, 1971 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Miscellaneous Actions, 1969 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Budget, 1979 (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Title III, Developing Institutions-Grant, 1974 (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Faculty Senate, 1968 (Box-folder 1/38)
    - Faculty Opinion Survey, Elvin Salisbury, Fall 1972 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Performing Arts, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3/31)
    - President's Advisory Council, 1983 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Retirement, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Paul Rickman-Resignation, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Membership-Local 1485, 1973 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Audit of College District, 1976 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Full Time Employees, Etc., 1975 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Travel Vouchers, Minority Affairs, etc., 1974-1976 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Travel Vouchers, Minority Affairs, etc., 1974-1976 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Official Letters, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Press and Memos, 1970-1978 (Box-folder 4/15)
    - William Russell-Correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Mauno Saari-Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 4/17)
    - Merger and Merger Talks, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Public Disclosure-Initiative 276, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 4/20)
    - Newsletters, Memos, etc., 1964-1968 (Box-folder 4/27)
    - Turner, Franklin R.-Press, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 4/30)
    - Correspondence, Working Papers, etc., 1973-1974 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Summer School, 1974 (Box-folder 9/21)
    - Parking, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 9/22)
    - Calendar Agreement, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Calendar Agreement, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Calendar Agreement, 1976 (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Newsletters, Memos, etc., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Newsletters, Memos, etc., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 10/15)
    - Newsletters, Memos, etc., 1970-1971 (Box-folder 10/16)
    - Franklin County Decision, 1975 (Box-folder 10/19)
    - Yakima Valley College-Press, Undated (Box-folder 10/20)
    - Yakima Valley College-Art Department, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 10/28)
  - ASSOCIATION FOR HIGHER EDUCATION, 1968-1986; SERIES V
    - Association for Higher Education-"Contract" Proposal, 1968 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Association for Higher Education-Negotiations, 1972 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Association for Higher Education-Election Materials, 1969 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1969-1970 (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1969-1971 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., Spring 1973 (Box-folder 9/26)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1973-1974 (Box-folder 9/27)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1973-1976 (Box-folder 9/28)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1974-1975 (Box-folder 9/29)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1975-1976 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1976-1977 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1977-1978 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1978-1979 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1979-1980 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1982-1983 (Box-folder 9/25)
    - Association for Higher Education-Meeting Materials, Memos, etc., 1984-1986 (Box-folder 9/24)
  - CONSTITUTIONS, 1972-1983; SERIES VI
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Constitution, 1972 (Box-folder 1/34)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Constitution, 1983 (Box-folder 1/37)
    - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers-Constitution (stencils), Undated (Box-folder Oversize box 6 (provisional))
  - ELECTIONS, 1968-1977; SERIES VII
    - Collective Bargaining Election, May 1968 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Collective Bargaining Election-Correspondence, 1969 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Election Rules Issue, 1970 (Box-folder 10/14)
    - Collective Bargaining Election, May 1971 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Collective Bargaining Election, 1971 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Collective Bargaining Election, 1973 (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Collective Bargaining Election, Part 1 of 3, 1977 (Box-folder 4/39)
    - Collective Bargaining Election, Part 1 of 3, 1977 (Box-folder 4/40)
    - Collective Bargaining Election, Part 1 of 3, 1977 (Box-folder 4/41)
    - Collective Bargaining Election, Part 2 of 3, 1977 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Collective Bargaining Election, Part 3 of 3, 1977 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Collective Bargaining Election, Part 3 of 3, 1977 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Master-Election Challenges, 1977 (Box-folder 5/34)
  - CONTRACT NEGOTIATIONS, 1968-1988; SERIES VIII
    - Representation Negotiation, 1968 (Box-folder 10/29)
    - Negotiated Policy Document, 1972 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Retroactivity-1973 Salaries (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Procedures for Negotiations (I), 1973 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Union Proposed Contract and Agreement, 1973 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement-Tentative Agreement, 1973 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement-Implementation, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Board Proposal and Counterproposal, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement-Lack of Enforcement, 1974 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Overview, 1974 (Box-folder 9/13)
    - Board Proposal, 1974 (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Union Proposal, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Various Loose Papers Regarding Negotiations, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Coaches, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement-Proposal, April 15, 1975 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement-Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Impasse-Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement, June 15, 1977 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement, 1977 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - 1977 Bargaining-Correspondence, etc. (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement-Proposal, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement, 1978 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement-Ratification (II), 1978 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement-Amended, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 10/25)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement-Letter Copies, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Meeting Log-1979 Negotiations (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Counselors, 1980 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Negotiated Policy Agreement-Correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Memo to Faculty from Negotiations Team, regarding "The New Agreement", 1981 (Box-folder 4/37)
    - Salary Increase, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6/27)
    - Salary Increase, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 6/28)
    - Collective Bargaining and Governance, 1983 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Salary Negotiations, 1988 (Box-folder 4/14)
  - UNION ASSOCIATIONS, 1965-1983; SERIES IX
    - Seattle Federation of Teachers, 1979 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Seattle Community College Federation of Teachers, 1965-1983 (Box-folder 4/18)
    - Mountain Vista Nursing Home, 1981 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Yakima and East Klickitat County Labor Council, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - American Federation of Teachers-State Materials, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 10/21)
    - Promotional Materials, Undated (Box-folder 10/24)
    - American Federation of Teachers-National Materials, 1962-1974 (Box-folder 10/27)
    - Washington Education Association, 1968 (Box-folder 10/30)
- American Federation of Teachers, Yakima Local 1485 records, 1969-1997; 4145-002; 2.00 cubic feet (2 boxes)
  Arranged into 2 Record Groups. Records Group 1 is divided into 7 Series.
  RECORD GROUP 1: AMERICAN FEDERATION OF TEACHERS, LOCAL 1485/YAKIMA VALLEY COLLEGE FEDERATION OF TEACHERS
  SERIES I: COLLECTIVE BARGAINING AND CONTRACTS
  SERIES II: CONTRACT ENFORCEMENT
  SERIES III: ELECTIONS
  SERIES IV: EXECUTIVE BOARD PROCEEDINGS
  SERIES V: LEGAL PROCEEDINGS
  SERIES VI: REDUCTIONS IN FORCE (RIF)
  SERIES VII: TENURE PROCESS
  RECORD GROUP 2: EDMONDS-EVERETT ASSOCIATION FOR HIGHER EDUCATION